Guide to the Department of Statistics, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Statistics, Yale University, records
1944-1991
RU 144
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
17.25
The records consist of subject, student and personnel files concerning the activities and operations of the Yale Department of Statistics. Also included are videotapes of the department's celebration of its 25th anniversary and the 70th birthday of Francis J. Anscombe.
Yale University. Dept. of Statistics
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 14-B (YRG 14-B), Records of academic departments and programs of the Yale Faculty of Arts and Sciences.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See inventory for details. Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of subject, student and personnel files concerning the activities and operations of the Yale Department of Statistics. Also included are videotapes of the department's celebration of its 25th anniversary and the 70th birthday of Francis J. Anscombe.
Statistics -- Study and teaching; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Departments; Videotapes; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Dept. of Statistics
- Records, 1944-1981; Accession 1987-A-002
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2017
  - Committee on Statistics, 1944-1963
    - American Statistical Association: Panel Discussion and Letters (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Committee on Statistics -- General File, 1944-1953 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Committee on the Course in Statistics at Yale College, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Committee on Statistics, 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Proposal by Committee to Establish Department of Statistics at Yale, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Committee Administration, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Committee Meetings/Business, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Attendance Records, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence -- Visiting Lecturers, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Housing/Visit Arrangements, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Requisitions, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Travel Expense Reports and Data, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Accounts, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Books and Journals, 1950-1952 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Committee Business, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Repairs to Calculating Machines, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Invoices and Receipts, 1952-1959 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Statistics 157b, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Statistics Broadcasts, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Library Book Lists, 1954-1957 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Expenditures, 1955-1959 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Fellowships, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Office Machines, 1956-(1964) (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Committee (Princeton) on Project Research and Inventions, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Lectures, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Miscellaneous Letters, 1957-1962 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Princeton Library, 1957-1962 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - "For File", 1958 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Finances, 1958-1965 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence, 1959-1963 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Committee Research -- Hartford Insurance, 1959-1963 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - "Letters to be Answered", 1961-1963 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Miscellaneous Letters, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - New Jersey Division of Motor Vehicles, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Architect (Kirtland Hall), 1963 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Computers, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Miscellaneous, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Chairman F.J. Anscombe, 1963-1966
    - Air Force Office of Scientific Research (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Annual Reports (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Department Chairman -- Miscellaneous Mail (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Department Planning (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Fifth Berkeley Symposium (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Junior Appointment Inquiries (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Kirtland Hall (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - National Aeronautics and Space Administration (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - National Defense Graduate Fellowship Program (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - National Science Foundation (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - NSF-GP-6 James -- July 1, 1962 - June 30, 1964; 8400-31-45000 (Box 5, Folder 30 - 32)
    - Seminars (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Telephone (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Chairman F.J. Anscombe, 1966-1969
    - Worrall, John G (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Advisory Committee of the Social Sciences (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Annual Reports (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Computer Center (Box 6, Folder 20-23)
    - Courses (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Defense Documentation Center (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Department Chairman - Miscellaneous Mail (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Draft (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Educational Testing Service (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Employee Relations Department (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Faculty Appointments (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Foreign Student Information (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Graduate Programs (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - International Business Machines Contract (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Inventory of Physical Facilities (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Languauge Requirement (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - National Defense Fellowship Program (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - National Science Foundation Traineeships (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - NONR 609 (52). Office of Naval Research (Box 7, Folder 39-41)
    - Offfce of Naval Research 8400-31-42045 (Box 8, Folder 42-44)
    - Personnel (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Seminar Notices (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Statistics 8400-31-66307-4201 (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - Statistics 8600-31-66542 (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - Undergraduate Program (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - Yale College (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Chairman L.J. Savage, 1969-1971
    - Air Force Proposal (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - American Mathematical Society (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Annual Reports (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - APL Service (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Centrex (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Courses (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Department Chairman -- Miscellaneous Mail (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Faculty Appointments (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - General Examination (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Graduate School (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Graduate School Requests Sent to Admissions (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - International Business Machines 8400-31-66802 (Box 9, Folder 18 - 20)
    - Inventory of Physical Facilities (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Junior Appointments (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Language Requirement (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - National Aeronautics and Space Administration (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - National Institutes of Health Research Grant (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - National Science Foundation (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - National Science Foundation Graduate Traineeship (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - NONR 609(52) -- Office of Naval Research (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Office of Naval Research 8400-31-42045 (Box 10, Folder 30 - 33)
    - Seminar Notices (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Sigma Xi (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Statistics 8400-31-66307-4201 (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Statistics 8400-31-67367 (Box 11, Folder 37 - 38)
    - Undergraduate Program (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Yale College (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Chairman J.A. Hartigan, 1972-1975
    - Affirmative Action
      - Faculty (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Students (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - American Mathematical Society (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Annual Report (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Army Research Office (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Computer Center
      - General (Box 12, Folder 10 - 12)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 12, Folder 13)
      - 1974-1975 (Box 13, Folder 14)
      - 1975-1976 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Educational Testing Service (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - General Examination (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Graduate School (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Graduate School Requests Sent to Admissions (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - International Business Machines 600A-31-66802 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Junior Appointment Inquiries (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Language Requirement (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Library (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - National Aeronautics and Space Administration (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - National Science Foundation (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Seminar Notes (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Summer Programs (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Survey of the Teaching of Statistics, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Telephone (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Undergraduate Programs (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Yale College (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Chairman I.R. Savage, 1975-1978
    - Affirmative Action (Students) (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Air Force Office of Scientific Research (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - American Mathematical Society (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Annals of Statistics (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Annual Report (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Army Research Office (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Committee on Teaching Statistics (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Computer Center
      - 1976-1977 (Box 15, Folder 8 - 9)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Courses (Box 16, Folder 12 - 13)
    - Department (Box 16, Folder 14 - 16)
    - Department Chairman -- Miscellaneous Mail (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Graduate Program (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Graduate School (Box 16, Folder 19 - 20)
    - Graduate School Requests Sent to Admissions (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Grants and Contracts (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Institute of Mathematical Statistics Conference
      - Registrations (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Inventory of Physical Facilities (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Junior Appointment Inquiries (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - Large Data Sets Project (Box 17, Folder 27 - 28)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - National Institute of Health Research Grant (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - National Science Foundation (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - Office of Naval Research (Box 18, Folder 32 - 33)
    - Seminars (Box 18, Folder 34)
    - Seminar Notices (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - Seminar Speakers (Box 18, Folder 36)
    - Space Function Survey, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 37)
    - Statistics N0014-67-A-0097-0014 (Box 18, Folder 38 - 39)
    - Statistics 42107 NONR-G-00020-74 (Box 18, Folder 40)
    - Statistics 46011 P043779 (Box 19, Folder 41)
    - Statistics 46052-DCR-75-08374 (Box 19, Folder 42 - 44)
    - Statistics 600A-31-42115 (Box 19, Folder 45 - 46)
    - Statistics 600A-31-42115 (Box 20, Folder 47)
    - Statistics 600A-31-46067 (Box 20, Folder 48)
    - Statistics 600A-31-46138 (Box 20, Folder 49)
    - Statistics 600A-31-66307-4201 (Box 20, Folder 50)
    - Statistics 8600-31-66542 (Box 20, Folder 51)
    - Statistics Day Project, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 52)
    - Statistics Day
      - 1977 (Box 20, Folder 53)
      - 1978 (Box 20, Folder 54)
    - Summer Programs (Box 20, Folder 55)
    - Telephone (Box 20, Folder 56)
    - Yale College (Box 20, Folder 57)
  - Chairman I.R. Savage, 1978-1981
    - Affirmative Action (Faculty) (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Air Force Office of Scientific Research (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Alumni Fund (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - American Mathematical Society (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Annual Report (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Appointments (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Associates Program (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Consulting Activities (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Courses (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Department (Box 21, Folder 10 - 13)
    - Employee Relations Department (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Foreign Student and Scholar Office (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Graduate School (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Grants and Contracts (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Guide to Requirements for the PhD Degree in Statistics (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Institute of Mathematical Statistics (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Inventory of Moveable Equipment (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Inventory of Physical Facilities (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Joint Appointment (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - Language Requirement (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Master's Programs (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - Meeting: Graduate Programs in Statistics (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - National Science Foundation (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - Office of Naval Research (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - Seminars (Box 22, Folder 30 - 31)
    - Seminars, 1979-1980 (Box 22, Folder 32)
    - Seminar Notices (Box 22, Folder 33)
    - Social Science Research Committee (Box 22, Folder 34)
    - Space Function Survey, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - Statistical Analysis Competition Entries (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - Statistics Day
      - 1980 (Box 23, Folder 37)
      - 1981 (Box 23, Folder 38)
    - Statistics Lab (Box 23, Folder 39)
    - Statistics 46302-78-10496 (Box 23, Folder 40)
    - Statistics 46353-SOC-7818166 (Box 23, Folder 41)
    - Statistics 46515-MCS-8102280 (Box 23, Folder 42)
    - Statistics 46516-MCS-8102725 (Box 23, Folder 43)
    - Statistics 600A-31-41131 (Box 23, Folder 44 - 45)
    - Statistics 600A-31-42115 (Box 24, Folder 46 - 47)
    - Statistics 600A-31-46376 (Box 24, Folder 48 - 49)
    - Statistics 600B-31-87842 (Box 24, Folder 50 - 52)
    - Statistics 8660-31-66542 (Box 24, Folder 53)
    - Summer Programs (Box 24, Folder 54)
    - Telephone (Box 24, Folder 55)
    - Yale College (Box 24, Folder 56)
  - Restricted: Personnel and Students
    - Old Records: Committee on Statistics
      - Personnel -- Committee on Statistics, 1955-1959 (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Staff, 1956-1962 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - 1963-1966
      - Bursary Students (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - Grades (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - Graduate School (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - Graduate Student Budgets (Box 25, Folder 8)
      - Graduate Student Inquiries (Box 25, Folder 9 - 11)
    - 1966-1969
      - American Mathematical Society (Box 25, Folder 14)
      - Bursary Students (Box 25, Folder 15)
      - Grades (Box 25, Folder 16)
      - Graduate School (Box 26, Folder 17)
      - Graduate Student Budgets (Box 26, Folder 18)
      - Graduate Student Inquiries
        - 1966-1967 (Box 26, Folder 19 - 20)
        - 1968-1969 (Box 26, Folder 21 - 23)
      - Junior Appointment Inquiries (Box 26, Folder 24)
      - Recommendations (Box 26, Folder 27)
      - Student Recommendations (Box 26, Folder 28)
    - 1969-1971
      - Bursary Students (Box 27, Folder 30)
      - Grades (Box 27, Folder 31)
      - Graduate Student Budgets (Box 27, Folder 32)
      - Graduate Student Inquiries
        - 1969-1970 (Box 27, Folder 33 - 34)
        - 1970-1971 (Box 27, Folder 35 - 37)
      - Junior Appointment Inquiries (Box 28, Folder 40)
      - Recommendations (Box 28, Folder 41)
    - 1972-1975
      - Bursary Students (Box 28, Folder 42)
      - Faculty Appointments (Box 28, Folder 43)
      - Grades (Box 28, Folder 44 - 45)
      - Graduate Student Report (Box 28, Folder 46)
      - Graduate School Inquiries
        - 1972-1973 (Box 28, Folder 47 - 48)
        - 1973-1974 (Box 29, Folder 49)
      - Recommendations (Box 29, Folder 50)
    - 1975-1978
      - Bursary Students (Box 29, Folder 51)
      - Employee Relations Department (Box 29, Folder 52)
      - Grades (Box 29, Folder 53)
      - Graduate School Budget (Box 29, Folder 54)
      - Graduate School Inquiries
        - 1975-1976 (Box 29, Folder 55 - 56)
        - 1976-1977 (Box 30, Folder 57)
        - 1977-1978 (Box 30, Folder 58 - 60)
      - Joint Appointments (Political Science-Sociology-Statistics) (Box 30, Folder 61)
      - Joint Appointments (Box 30, Folder 62)
      - Junior Appointments (Box 31, Folder 63 - 65)
      - Recommendations (Box 31, Folder 66)
      - Statistics 46052-DCR-75-08574 (Box 31, Folder 67 - 68)
    - 1978-1981
      - Biostatistics Exam (Box 31, Folder 69)
      - Bursary Students (Box 31, Folder 70)
      - Grades (Box 31, Folder 71 - 72)
      - Graduate School Budget (Box 32, Folder 73)
      - Joint Appointments (Box 32, Folder 74)
      - Junior Appointment Inquiries (Box 32, Folder 75)
      - Recommendations (Box 32, Folder 76)
- 25th anniversary celebration videotapes, 1987; Accession 1989-A-104
  Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy of non-commercially produced items for their personal use should consult the ordering reproductions information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
  - 25th anniversary celebration videotapes, 1987 (Box 1)
- Records, 1984-1988; Accession 1994-A-051
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2023
  - Academic Appointment (Box 1)
  - Alumni Fund (Box 1)
  - American Mathematical Society (Box 1)
  - Annual Report, 1984-1987 (Box 1)
  - Biostatistics Exam (Box 1)
  - Bursary Students (Box 1)
  - Computer Center (Box 1)
  - Courses
    - 1985-1986 (Box 1)
    - 1986-1987 (Box 1)
    - 1987-1988 (Box 1)
  - Department (Box 1)
  - Examinations (Box 1)
  - Grades (Box 1)
  - Graduate School (Box 1)
  - Graduate School Budget (Box 1)
  - Grants and Contracts (Box 1)
  - I-9 Forms (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Physical Plant (Box 2)
  - Recruiting (Box 2)
  - Recruiting, 1987-1988 (Box 2)
  - Statistics Celebration (Box 2)
  - Statistical Laboratory (Box 2)
  - Statistics Day
    - 1985 (Box 2)
    - 1986 (Box 2)
    - 1987 (Box 2)
  - Seminars, 1987-1988 (Box 2)
  - Summer Jobs (Box 2)
  - Summer Programs (Box 2)
  - Undergraduate Programs (Box 2)
  - Visitors (Box 2)
  - Yale College (Box 2)
- Records, 1987-1991; Accession 1996-A-013
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2026
  Scope and Contents
  No boxes 1 and 2.
  - Alumni Fund (Box 3)
  - American Mathematical Society (Box 3)
  - Annual Report, 1987-1989 (Box 3)
  - Applied Math (Box 3)
  - Appointment Procedure (Box 3)
  - Biostatistics Exam (Box 3)
  - Bursary Students (Box 3)
  - Computer Center (Box 3)
  - Courses
    - 1988-1989 (Box 3)
    - 1989-1990 (Box 3)
    - 1990-1991 (Box 3)
  - Department (Box 3)
  - Department Chairman (Box 3)
  - Grades (Box 3)
  - Graduate School (Box 4)
  - Graduate School Admissions (Box 4)
  - Grants and Contracts (Box 4)
  - Honorary Degrees (Box 4)
  - I-9 Forms (Box 4)
  - I-9 Forms (former employees) (Box 4)
  - Inventory, Moving Equipment (Box 4)
  - Junior Appointment Inquiries (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - National Science Foundation (Box 4)
  - Personnel (Box 5)
  - Peterson's Guides (Box 5)
  - Physical Plant (Box 5)
  - Recruiting
    - 1988-1989 (Box 5)
    - 1989-1990 (Box 5)
    - 1990-1991 (Box 5)
  - Seminars
    - 1988-1989 (Box 5)
    - 1989-1990 (Box 5)
    - 1990-1991 (Box 5)
  - Space Function Survey (Box 5)
  - Statistical Laboratory (Box 5)
  - Statistics Day
    - 1988 (Box 5)
    - 1989 (Box 5)
  - Telephone (Box 5)
  - Visitors (Box 5)
  - Yale College (Box 5)